AD.MC.031
AbuDhabi
Al Qassim Family Collection
1960-1980
AD.MC.031
AbuDhabi
2.0 Paige boxes
Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr.
Object AD_MC_031
Conditions Governing Access note
Digitization of this collection is in process.
Custodial History note
Akkasah, the Center for Photography at NYU Abu Dhabi, acquired the collection in February 2017.
Scope and Contents note
This collection of photos represents the personal photography of Mr. Abdulghafoor Alqasim from different areas of United Arab Emirates. The images date from both before and after the birth of UAE as a country in 1971 as well as Mr. Abdulghafoor's trips to other countries throughout the world. The collection reflects Mr. Abdulghafoor's interest in photography when he was a student in Dubai in the nineteen-sixties and extends decades into the era of digital photography. Akkasah has worked closely with Mr. Abdulghafoor to assure that his family's photographs are digitally preserved not only for the sake of posterity but also to serve as important cultural documents of the birth and rapid growth of the United Arab Emirates as a nation.
- Al Qassim Family Collection Prints (Object AD_MC_031_ref168)
  - A reception for Rashid bin Saeed Al Maktoum during the grand opening of the Dubai Airport with an Iran Air plane in the background. 5.2 x 7.2 cm, 1960; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref1)
    Airplanes; Airports; Arabic Writing; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Events/Occasions; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Kandora/Dishdasha/Thawb; Men; Photographic Prints; Traditional Dress
  - A boy holding a rifle in Ras al-Khaimah. 8.7 x 6.3 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref2)
    Arabic Writing; Boys; Children; Deserts; Guns; Individual Portraits; Landscapes; Photographic Prints; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates
  - An Iran Air plane at the old Dubai Airport. 6.2 x 8.8 cm, 1960; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref3)
    Airplanes; Airports; Arabic Writing; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints
  - Group trip to Ras al-Khaimah. 6.5 x 8.7 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr.; Rods Photo Studio, Dubai, Trucial States (UAE) (Object AD_MC_031_ref4)
    Arabic Writing; Cars; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Hats; Men; Photographic Prints; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates; Trucks
  - Group trip to Al Kharan, Ras al-Khaimah. 6.9 x 8.8 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr.; Rods Photo Studio, Dubai, Trucial States (UAE) (Object AD_MC_031_ref5)
    Arabic Writing; Cars; Deserts; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates; Tents; Trips
  - A picnic trip in the desert. 6.9 x 8.8 cm, Circa 1960-1969; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref6)
    Arabic Writing; Cars; Deserts; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Men; Photographic Prints; Picnic; Smoking; United Arab Emirates
  - Al-Maktoom Bridge in Dubai. 7.2 x 9.0 cm, 19 February 1964; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref7)
    Arabic Writing; Architecture; Bridges; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; History; Landscapes; Photographic Prints; Seas
  - A school classroom during a test. 6.6 x 8.5 cm, 18 May 1962; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref9)
    Boys; Children; Classrooms; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Schools/Education; Students; Teachers; United Arab Emirates
  - A portrait of a boy in front of his house in Deira, Dubai. 6.2 x 8.8 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref10)
    Arabic Writing; Boys; Children; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Houses; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Windows
  - Al-Fahidi Fort in Dubai. 6.6 x 8.7 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref11)
    Arabic Writing; Architecture; Buildings; Deserts; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Forts; Gelatin Silver Prints; Islamic Architecture; Photographic Prints
  - Group trip to Kharran, Ras Al-Khaimah. 6.7 x 8.7 cm, 8 March 1962; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref12)
    Arabic Writing; Deserts; Field-trip; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Guns; Landscapes; Men; Photographic Prints; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates; Smoking
  - Men at a rest area during their trip to Ras Al-Khaimah. 6.8 x 8.6 cm, 25 August 1964; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref13)
    Arabic Writing; Clothing; Field-trip; Gelatin Silver Prints; Groups, Social; Hats; Men; Photographic Prints; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates
  - Group portrait of men during their trip to Ras Al-Khaimah. 6.7 x 8.8 cm, 1968; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref14)
    Arabic Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Groups, Social; Landscapes; Men; Photographic Prints; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates; Trees
  - Field trip to Kharan, Ras Al-Khaimah. 6.7 x 8.7 cm, 25 August 1964; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref15)
    Arabic Writing; Boys; Cars; Clothing; Field-trip; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Landscapes; Men; Photographic Prints; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates; Trees
  - Field trip to Kharan, Ras Al-Khaimah. 6.6 x 9.0 cm, 1968; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref16)
    Arabic Writing; Carpets/Rugs; Field-trip; Gelatin Silver Prints; Landscapes; Lanterns/Lamps; Men; Photographic Prints; Picnic; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates; Trees
  - View of Dubai in the sixties from the minaret of a mosque. 6.9 x 8.8 cm, Circa 1960-1969; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref17)
    Arabic Writing; Architecture; Buildings; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; History; Landscapes; Photographic Prints
  - View of Dubai from the minaret of a mosque. 7.0 x 8.9 cm, Circa 1960-1969; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref18)
  - Al Shaab School in Dubai. 6.3 x 8.5 cm, 16 May 1962; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref19)
    Arabic Writing; Buildings; Cars; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Flags; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Schools/Education; Students
  - Khatt, Ras Al-Khaimah. 6.6 x 8.7 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref20)
    Arabic Writing; Cars; Deserts; Gelatin Silver Prints; Landscapes; Palm trees; Photographic Prints; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates; Trees
  - Al-Salehia, Ras Al-Khaimah. 6.7 x 8.7 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref21)
    Arabic Writing; Farms; Gelatin Silver Prints; Landscapes; Palm trees; Photographic Prints; Plants; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates
  - Al-Salehia, Ras Al-Khaimah. 6.8 x 8.7 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref22)
  - The minaret of a mosque in Dubai. 8.7 x 6.4 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref23)
    Arabic Writing; Architecture; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; History; Mosques; Photographic Prints
  - Khatt, Ras Al-Khaimah. 6.5 x 8.6 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref24)
    Arabic Writing; Architecture; Deserts; Gelatin Silver Prints; Houses; Landscapes; Palm trees; Photographic Prints; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates; Trees
  - One of the oldest buildings near Dubai Creek in Dubai. 6.8 x 8.8 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref25)
    Arabic Writing; Architecture; Balcony/Terrace; Buildings; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints
  - Portrait of a young man on the Al-Maktoum Bridge. 6.8 x 9.0 cm, 19 February 1964; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref26)
    Arabic Writing; Bridges; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Motorcycles; Photographic Prints
  - Boy scouts in their school. 6.7 x 8.7 cm, 18 May 1962; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref27)
    Arabic Writing; Architecture; Boys; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Schools/Education; Scouts; United Arab Emirates
  - A fort on a mountain in Oman. 6.8 x 8.6 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref28)
    Arabic Writing; Forts; Gelatin Silver Prints; Landscapes; Mountains; Oman; Photographic Prints
  - Dubai High School. 6.7 x 8.7 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref29)
    Arabic Writing; Architecture; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Schools/Education
  - Al-Fahidi Fort in Dubai. 6.3 x 8.8 cm, Circa 1960-1969; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref30)
    Arabic Writing; Architecture; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Forts; Gelatin Silver Prints; History; Photographic Prints
  - The Iranian School in Dubai. 6.6 x 8.7 cm, Circa 1960-1969; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref31)
    Arabic Writing; Architecture; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; History; Iran; Photographic Prints; Schools/Education
  - A tank for drinkable water from Al Awir in Dubai. 6.9 x 8.8 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref32)
    Arabic Writing; Drinking; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Tanks; Water
  - Preparation of the Eid sacrifice during an outing in Ras Al-Khaimah. 6.3 x 8.8 cm, Circa 1960-1969; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref33)
    Arabic Writing; Boys; Eid; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates; Sheep
  - Mountains in Masafi. 6.7 x 8.9 cm, 25 February 1965; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref34)
    Arabic Writing; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Landscapes; Mountains; Photographic Prints; United Arab Emirates
  - Preparing food during a trip in Al Kharran in Ras Al-Khaimah. 6.8 x 8.8 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref35)
    Arabic Writing; Clothing; Food; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates; Trips; Utensils
  - Rifle training in the desert. 6.1 x 9.0 cm, 19 November 1965; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref36)
    Arabic Writing; Boys; Deserts; Gelatin Silver Prints; Guns; Landscapes; Photographic Prints; United Arab Emirates
  - School trip to Masafi. 9.0 x 6.6 cm, 25 February 1965; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref37)
    Arabic Writing; Boys; Carpets/Rugs; Field-trip; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates; Schools/Education
  - Al-Salehia, Ras Al-Khaimah. 8.7 x 6.4 cm, Circa 1960-1969; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref38)
    Arabic Writing; Boys; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates; Smoking; Taxi; Trucks
  - Students in a classroom during a test in Dubai. 6.1 x 8.6 cm, 18 May 1962; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref39)
    Arabic Writing; Architecture; Boys; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Schools/Education; Students; Teachers
  - Irrigation system on a farm. 8.8 x 6.9 cm, Circa 1960-1969; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref40)
    Arabic Writing; Farmers; Farms; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; Palm trees; Photographic Prints; Sharjah, United Arab Emirates; United Arab Emirates; Water
  - Boys swimming in Ras Al-Khaimah. 6.6 x 8.7 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref41)
    Arabic Writing; Boys; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates; Swimming Pools; Water
  - Trip to Ras Al-Khaimah's mineral springs. 6.7 x 8.7 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref42)
    Arabic Writing; Boys; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates; Trips; Trucks
  - Entrance to a house in Dubai. 6.9 x 8.9 cm, Circa 1960-1969; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref43)
    Arabic Writing; Bicycles; Boys; Doors; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Houses; Men; Photographic Prints; Walking; Windows
  - Backyard garden in Dubai. 6.5 x 8.7 cm, Circa 1960-1969; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref44)
    Agriculture; Animals; Arabic Writing; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints
  - Goat in a house backyard in Dubai. 6.7 x 8.7 cm, Circa 1960-1969; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref45)
    Animals; Arabic Writing; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Goats; Houses; Photographic Prints
  - A classroom. 6.2 x 8.6 cm, 18 May 1962; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref46)
    Arabic Writing; Classrooms; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Schools/Education; Students
  - A school's football field. 6.5 x 8.4 cm, Circa 1960-1969; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref47)
    Arabic Writing; Boys; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Fields; Football; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Schools/Education; Students
  - Highschool football field in Dubai. 6.5 x 8.6 cm, Circa 1960-1969; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref48)
    Arabic Writing; Boys; Cars; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Fields; Football; Gelatin Silver Prints; Houses; Men; Photographic Prints; Schools/Education; Uniforms
  - Students in classroom in Masafi Area, Dubai. 6.6 x 8.8 cm, 25 February 1965; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref49)
    Arabic Writing; Boys; Classrooms; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Schools/Education; Students; Tables
  - Portrait of Abd Alghafour on a desert trip. 6.6 x 8.6 cm, 8 April 1962; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref50)
    Arabic Writing; Boys; Deserts; Gelatin Silver Prints; Grass; Photographic Prints; Trees; United Arab Emirates
  - Group trip to the desert. 6.9 x 8.8 cm, Circa 1960-1969; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref51)
    Arabic Writing; Cars; Deserts; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; United Arab Emirates
  - Portrait of Abd Alghafour Al-Qassim in Khatt, Ras Al-Khaimah. 6.6 x 8.5 cm, Circa 1960-1969; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref52)
    Arabic Writing; Boys; Coats/Jackets; Gelatin Silver Prints; Lanterns/Lamps; Photographic Prints; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates
  - The garden of the ruler of Ras Al-Khaimah Sheikh Saqer. 6.8 x 9.0 cm, 25 February 1965; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref53)
    Arabic Writing; Boys; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates
  - School trip to Masafi, Dubai. 7.3 x 11.0 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref54)
    Arabic Writing; Boys; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Field-trip; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Schools/Education; Students
  - Group trip to Al Batinah, Oman. 6.8 x 8.8 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref55)
    Arabic Writing; Boys; Cars; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Mountains; Oman; Photographic Prints; Plants
  - Group portrait in Ras Al-Khaimah. 6.7 x 8.7 cm, 8 March 1962; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref56)
    Arabic Writing; Deserts; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Plants; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates
  - A school in Dubai. 6.7 x 8.7 cm, 18 May 1965; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref57)
    Arabic Writing; Classrooms; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Palm trees; Photographic Prints; Schools/Education; Students
  - Houses made from palm leaves (arish), Dubai. 9.0 x 6.2 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref58)
    Arabic Writing; Boats/Ships; Docks/Piers/Jetties; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Houses; Palm trees; Photographic Prints; Water
  - The reception of Sheikh Rashid Al Maktoum at the Dubai Airpot. 6.6 x 8.8 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref59)
    Airports; Arabic Writing; Cars; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Streets/Roads
  - Landscape of Dubai. 6.9 x 9.0 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref60)
    Buildings; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Houses; Landscapes; Photographic Prints; Tanks; Trees
  - Landscape of Dubai with view of Khor Dubai. 8.9 x 14.0, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref61)
    Arabic Writing; Buildings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Houses; Landscapes; Photographic Prints; Ships; Water
  - Landscape of Khor Dubai from a mosque in Bur Dubai. 8.6 x 14.0, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref62)
    Arabic Writing; Buildings; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Landscapes; Photographic Prints; Water
  - Landscape of Khor Dubai. 8.9 x 14.0 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref63)
    Arabic Writing; Boats/Ships; Buildings; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Landscapes; Photographic Prints; Water
  - Landscape of Dubai. 8.9 x 14.0 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref64)
    Arabic Writing; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Houses; Landscapes; Photographic Prints
  - Iranian School in Dubai. 8.9 x 14.0 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref65)
    Arabic Writing; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Schools/Education
  - Khor Dubai. 8.9 x 14.0 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref66)
    Arabic Writing; Boats/Ships; Buildings; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Houses; Photographic Prints; Ships; Water
  - The old Dubai Airport. 6.6 x 8.8 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref67)
    Airports; Arabic Writing; Buildings; Cars; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints
  - A reception for Sheikh Rashid Al Maktoum at the Dubai Airport. 5.5 x 7.3 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref68)
    Airports; Arabic Writing; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Sheikhs; Traditional Dress
  - A boat in Khor Dubai 6.2 x 8.8 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref69)
    Arabic Writing; Boats/Ships; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Water
  - Water tank in Bur Dubai. 6.4 x 8.8 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref70)
    Arabic Writing; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Tanks; Water
  - Al Maktoum Bridge in Dubai. 7.1 x 9.0 cm, 19 Februrary 1964; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref71)
    Arabic Writing; Boats/Ships; Bridges; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Water
  - Reception of Sheikh Rashid Al Maktoum at the Dubai Airport. 5.5 x 7.4 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref72)
    Airplanes; Airports; Arabic Writing; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iran; Men; Photographic Prints; Sheikhs
  - Sheikh Rashid Al Maktoum in the Dubai Airport. 5.5 x 7.4 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref73)
    Airports; Arabic Writing; Crowds; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Sheikhs; Traditional Dress
  - A crowd welcoming Sheikh Rashid Al Maktoum at the Dubai airport. 6.7 x 8.8 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref74)
    Airports; Arabic Writing; Cars; Crowds; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Sheikhs
  - Entrance to Dubai airport's old building. 8.7 x 6.2 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref75)
    Airports; Arabic Writing; Crowds; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Flags; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints
  - Clock tower in Dubai. 6.3 x 8.9 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref76)
    Arabic Writing; Clocks/Watches; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Towers
  - School in Masafi, Dubai. 6.6 x 8.9 cm, 25 February 1965; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref77)
    Arabic Writing; Blackboard/Chalkboard; Classrooms; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Schools/Education; Teachers
  - View of Dubai from a mosque in Bur Dubai. 6.3 x 8.5 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref78)
    Arabic Writing; Architecture; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Houses; Landscapes; Palm trees; Photographic Prints; Tanks
  - Young boys in a school in Masafi, Dubai. 6.7 x 9.0 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref79)
    Arabic Writing; Boys; Classrooms; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Schools/Education; Students
  - Al Fahidi Fort, Dubai. 6.5 x 8.9 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref80)
    Arabic Writing; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Forts; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints
  - A man in front of Al Fahidi Fort, Dubai. 6.7 x 8.8 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref81)
    Arabic Writing; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Forts; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints
  - Dubai Airport's old building. 6.3 x 8.8 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref82)
    Airports; Arabic Writing; Cars; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints
  - Man in front of Dubai Airport's main entrance. 6.2 x 8.8 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref83)
    Airports; Arabic Writing; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Entrance; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints
  - Dubai's old airport. 6.1 x 8.8 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref84)
  - A building in Dubai. 6.9 x 8.8 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref85)
    Arabic Writing; Architecture; Buildings; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints
  - Customs point of Khor Dubai. 5.9 x 8.8 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref86)
    Arabic Writing; Boats/Ships; Buildings; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Water
  - Khatt Fort, Ras Al-Khaimah. 6.5 x 8.5 cm, 8 March 1962; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref87)
    Arabic Writing; Forts; Gelatin Silver Prints; Mountains; Photographic Prints; Ras Al-Khaimah, United Arab Emirates
  - Landscape of houses by the ocean. 6.9 x 8.8 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref88)
    Arabic Writing; Beaches; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Houses; Landscapes; Photographic Prints; Water
  - Dubai Landscape. 6.9 x 8.8 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref89)
    Arabic Writing; Buildings; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Houses; Landscapes; Photographic Prints
  - View of houses in Bur Dubai. 6.2 x 8.5 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref90)
    Arabic Writing; Architecture; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Houses; Landscapes; Photographic Prints
  - Landscape of Dubai. 6.8 x 8.8, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref91)
    Arabic Writing; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Houses; Photographic Prints; Water
  - Landscape view of Bur Dubai. 6.9 x 8.7 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref92)
  - View of Dubai. 6.9 x 8.8 cm, Undated; Al Qasim, Abdulghafoor, Mr. (Object AD_MC_031_ref93)
    Arabic Writing; Buildings; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Gelatin Silver Prints; Houses; Landscapes; Photographic Prints; Water